<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health Data Science | Zhiqiang Huo Profile</title>
    <link>http://localhost:12416/tags/health-data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:12416/tags/health-data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Health Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:12416/media/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Health Data Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:12416/tags/health-data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Mortality Prediction in Critically Ill Children During Interhospital Transports Using Explainable AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:12416/publication/npj_digital_medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:12416/publication/npj_digital_medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-ai-driven-mortality-prediction-for-interhospital-transport-in-pediatric-intensive-care&#34;&gt;🚑 AI-Driven Mortality Prediction for Interhospital Transport in Pediatric Intensive Care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to share our latest research on &lt;strong&gt;real-time mortality risk prediction&lt;/strong&gt; in critically ill children during &lt;strong&gt;interhospital transport&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;paediatric intensive care units (PICUs)&lt;/strong&gt;. This study, published in &lt;em&gt;npj Digital Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, introduces an &lt;strong&gt;explainable AI-powered model&lt;/strong&gt; designed to enhance &lt;strong&gt;clinical decision-making&lt;/strong&gt; in transport medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-findings&#34;&gt;🔬 Key Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time, dynamic risk prediction&lt;/strong&gt; – Continuously evaluates mortality risk based on &lt;strong&gt;vital signs, interventions, and transport conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explainable AI with SHAP analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – Identifies &lt;strong&gt;key clinical contributors&lt;/strong&gt; to risk estimation, enhancing trust and usability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher accuracy than traditional methods&lt;/strong&gt; – The &lt;strong&gt;PROMPT model&lt;/strong&gt; outperforms &lt;strong&gt;PIM3&lt;/strong&gt;, achieving &lt;strong&gt;AUROC of 0.83&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable deployment&lt;/strong&gt; – Designed for integration into &lt;strong&gt;ambulance monitoring systems&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;clinical decision-support tools&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-clinical-impact&#34;&gt;📢 Clinical Impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research provides &lt;strong&gt;clinicians with real-time, AI-driven insights&lt;/strong&gt; to support &lt;strong&gt;early interventions&lt;/strong&gt;, reduce &lt;strong&gt;preventable adverse events&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;optimize transport outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;PROMPT model&lt;/strong&gt; paves the way for &lt;strong&gt;next-generation predictive analytics in pediatric intensive care transport&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📄 &lt;strong&gt;Read the full article here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://assets-eu.researchsquare.com/files/rs-4909545/v1_covered_71b68edf-7610-4e3b-a972-442481dd2bed.pdf?c=1726733242&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publication Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Published in Intensive Care Medicine – Paediatric and Neonatal: High-Frequency Vital Signs Monitoring in Critically Ill Children</title>
      <link>http://localhost:12416/publication/icm-pn-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:12416/publication/icm-pn-journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-research-published-in-intensive-care-medicine--paediatric-and-neonatal&#34;&gt;🎉 Research Published in &lt;em&gt;Intensive Care Medicine – Paediatric and Neonatal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that our latest study has been &lt;strong&gt;published&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Intensive Care Medicine – Paediatric and Neonatal&lt;/em&gt;. This research, titled &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Distribution and Trajectory of Vital Signs from High-Frequency Continuous Monitoring in Critically Ill Children,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; provides &lt;strong&gt;new insights into pediatric intensive care&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-findings&#34;&gt;🔬 Key Findings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigates &lt;strong&gt;high-frequency vital sign monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; in critically ill children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzes &lt;strong&gt;physiological trajectories&lt;/strong&gt; to support &lt;strong&gt;early clinical interventions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offers &lt;strong&gt;data-driven insights&lt;/strong&gt; to enhance &lt;strong&gt;real-time patient monitoring in pediatric ICUs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study contributes to advancing &lt;strong&gt;digital health solutions&lt;/strong&gt; for pediatric critical care, aiming to support &lt;strong&gt;clinicians in making informed decisions&lt;/strong&gt; for better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-acknowledgments&#34;&gt;🙌 Acknowledgments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to our &lt;strong&gt;collaborators and participating institutions&lt;/strong&gt; for their dedication to this important research. Their support has been invaluable in driving innovation in &lt;strong&gt;pediatric intensive care&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📄 &lt;strong&gt;Read the full article here:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s44253-023-00018-x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Springer Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 &lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to further advancements in pediatric health informatics!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
